The power of seven become a league of one.
The League of Extraordinary Gentlemen is a fantasy, action,
thriller film directed by Stephen Norrington.
To prevent a world war from breaking out, famous characters from Victorian
literature band together to do battle against a cunning villain.
Allan Quatermain, played by Sean Connery.
Captain Nemo, played by Naseeruddin Shah.
Tom Sawyer, played by Shane West.
Mina Harker, played by Peta Wilson.
Dorian Gray, played by Stuart Townsend.
Dr. Henry Jekyll / Edward Hyde, played by Jason Flemyng.
The League of Extraordinary Gentlemen, also promoted as LXG, is a 2003 steampunk/dieselpunk superhero film based on some of the characters in the first volume
of the comic book series of the same name by Alan Moore and Kevin O'Neill, although the plot bears no similarity to that of the comic book.
Distributed by 20th Century Fox, it was released on 11 July 2003 in the
United States, and 17 October in the United Kingdom.
It was directed by Stephen Norrington and stars Sean Connery, Peta Wilson, Naseeruddin Shah,
Tony Curran, Stuart Townsend, Shane West, Jason Flemyng, and Richard Roxburgh.
It was Connery's final role in a theatrically released live-action
film before his retirement in 2007 and death in 2020.
As with the comic book source material, the film features prominent
pastiche and crossover themes set in the late 19th century.
It features an assortment of fictional literary characters appropriate
to the period who act as Victorian era superheroes.
It draws on the works of Jules Verne, H.
Wells, Bram Stoker, Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, Sir Henry Rider Haggard, Ian Fleming, Herman Melville,
Oscar Wilde, Robert Louis Stevenson, Edgar Allan Poe, Gaston Leroux, and Mark Twain.
It received generally unfavorable reviews but was financially successful, grossing over $179 million worldwide in theaters, and
earning rental revenue of $48.6 million and DVD sales (as of 2003) of $36.4 million, against its $78 million budget.
The film explores themes of saving the world, submarine,
venice, italy, immortality, based on comic.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.